<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xlingpaper PUBLIC "-//XMLmind//DTD XLingPap//EN"
"XLingPap.dtd">
<xlingpaper
version="2.24.0"
><styledPaper
><lingPaper
automaticallywrapinterlinears="yes"
useImageWidthSetToWidthOfExampleFigureOrChart="no"
version="2.28.0"
><frontMatter
><title
><object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> User Documentation</title
><author
>H. Andrew Black</author
><affiliation
>SIL International</affiliation
><emailAddress
>blackhandrew@gmail.com</emailAddress
><date
>12 August, 2024</date
><version
>Version 0.23.0 Beta</version
><version
>Copyright © 2023-2024 SIL International</version
><contents
></contents
></frontMatter
><section1
id="sIntro"
><secTitle
>Introduction</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> is a tool that enables you to write some <object
type="tFLExTrans"
></object
> transfer rules in a more linguist-friendly manner.</p
><p
><object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> is currently only available on 64-bit Windows computers.</p
><p
>Each rule defined in <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> describes a pattern that is used to match a source language structure and then map it to a transfer language structure.</p
><section2
id="sInstallation"
><secTitle
>Installation</secTitle
><p
>To install <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
>, obtain the installer from <link
href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1sFHyqW5gs-bLzAJS9lDTi09uagKf9z-n/view"
>https://​drive.​google.​com/​file/​d/​1sFHyqW5gs-bLzAJS9lDTi09uagKf9z-n/​view</link
>.</p
><p
>Note that <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> needs to be invoked from within <object
type="tFLExTrans"
></object
>.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sInvocation"
><secTitle
>Invocation</secTitle
><p
>You use a command line to invoke <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
>. The arguments are as in <exampleRef
letter="xCommandLine"
num="xCommandLine"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xCommandLine"
><chart
>FLExTransRuleAssistant &lt;rule-file&gt; &lt;source/target-FLEx-category/features&gt; (&lt;max vars&gt;)<br
></br
><br
></br
>&lt;rule-file&gt; Specifies the FLExTrans transfer rule file.<br
></br
><br
></br
>&lt;source/target-FLEx-category/features&gt; Specifies the XML file with both source and target categories and features.<br
></br
><br
></br
>(max vars&gt; Specifies the optional max number of variables to show in values (default is 4)</chart
></example
><pc
>If the &lt;rule-file&gt; does not already exist, then <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> will create it.</pc
></section2
><section2
id="sAppearance"
><secTitle
>Appearance</secTitle
><p
><object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> looks something like what is shown in <exampleRef
letter="xRuleGenOverview"
num="xRuleGenOverview"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xRuleGenOverview"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='650'"
src="Resources/RuleGen.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>There are two panes. The left one contains one transfer rule per line. The right pane shows a tree diagram of the selected rule. The right pane has two phrases. The left one is the source phrase and the right is the target phrase. In the source phrase, when a word has a category, it is shown in red immediately below the word. In the target phrase, a word with a category is shown in a grayed out red and in italics. While one can edit the category of a word in the source phrase, one cannot edit the category of a word in the target phrase.</p
><p
>When a target word is marked as being the head, it is shown in bold, as are any of its features.</p
><p
>The “Save” button is used to save changes made to rules or newly added rules.</p
><p
>The “Save &amp; Create” button is used to save changes made to rules or newly added rules and then create the currently selected rule in the <object
type="tFLExTrans"
></object
> rule file.<endnote
id="nCreate"
><p
>There will be two numbers separated by a space output to stdout with this option. The first will always be a 1. The second will be the zero-based index of the currently selected rule.</p
></endnote
> A validity check will also be applied to this rule. If any issue is found, an error dialog message will be shown with an explanation of what the issue is. The program will not exit until all validity checks pass.</p
><p
>The “Save &amp; Create All” button is used to save changes made to rules or newly added rules and then create all the rules in the <object
type="tFLExTrans"
></object
> rule file.<endnote
id="nCreateAll"
><p
>The number 2 will be output to stdout.</p
></endnote
> A validity check will also be applied to every rule. If any issue is found, an error dialog message will be shown with an explanation of what the issue is. It will also indicate which rule had the problem. The program will not exit until all validity checks pass.</p
><p
>The “Help” button is used to get this user documentation file or to show the “About” dialog box.</p
><p
>Whenever you use either the “Save &amp; Create” or “Save &amp; Create All” buttons, <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> will close.</p
><p
>Under the list of rules is a button labeled “Set disjoint gender features.” This is for a special case. See section <sectionRef
sec="sDisjointFeatureSets"
></sectionRef
>.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
id="sEditRules"
><secTitle
>Editing rules</secTitle
><p
>You can create new rules, rearrange them, or delete them by right-clicking on one. You will then see a context menu like what is in <exampleRef
letter="xRulesContextMenu"
num="xRulesContextMenu"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xRulesContextMenu"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='1250'"
src="Resources/RuleContextMenu.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>Use the "Rule Name:" text box to add or edit the name of a rule.</p
><p
>Use the “Description” text box to more thoroughly describe the rule, indicate what motivated the rule, and/or give some examples.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sEditTree"
><secTitle
>Editing trees</secTitle
><p
>The right pane contains a simplified tree diagram. Each such diagram has two parts: a source phrase is on the left and the corresponding target phrase is on the right. Every phrase will always have at least one word in it.</p
><p
></p
><section2
id="sEditWord"
><secTitle
>Editing a word</secTitle
><p
>When you click on a word item in the tree, the context menu shown in <exampleRef
letter="xWordContrextMenu"
num="xWordContrextMenu"
></exampleRef
> appears.</p
><example
num="xWordContrextMenu"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='1250'"
src="Resources/WordContextMenu.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>Select the item you wish to use. They are as follows:</p
><ul
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Duplicate</object
>: creates a complete copy of the current word.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Change number</object
>: modifies the word's number. If you choose a number of another word, then that other word will be set to the original number of the word you are changing.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Mark as head</object
>: labels this word as being the head of the phrase. This is only available for target words. If another word had been marked as being the head, then that other word will no longer be marked as the head. That is, only one word can be marked as the head.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Remove head marking</object
>: removes any head marking on this word. This is only available for target words.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert new before</object
>: inserts a new word item before the selected word.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert new after</object
>: inserts a new word item after the selected word.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert prefix</object
>: inserts an affix item labeled as a prefix. This is available only if the selected word has no affix items yet.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert suffix</object
>: inserts an affix item labeled as a suffix. This is available only if the selected word has no affix items yet.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert category</object
>: inserts a category item. This is available only if the selected word has no category item yet.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert feature</object
>: inserts a feature item. This is only available when a category has been set. The list of available features depends on the set of valid features defined in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> for the category of the word.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Move left</object
>: moves the selected word to the left.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Move right</object
>: moves the selected word to the right.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Delete</object
>: removes the selected word.</li
></ul
></section2
><section2
id="sEditCategory"
><secTitle
>Editing a category</secTitle
><p
>When you click on a category item in a word in the source phrase, the context menu shown in <exampleRef
letter="xCategoryContextMenu"
num="xCategoryContextMenu"
></exampleRef
> appears.</p
><example
num="xCategoryContextMenu"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='1250'"
src="Resources/CategoryContextMenu.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>The Category chooser appears if you choose “Edit.” Which categories are listed in the chooser depends on whether the category is in the source or the target portion of the tree diagram. <object
type="tFLExTrans"
></object
> gives <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> the list of categories for the source <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> project and the target <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> project. In one case, the category chooser looked like what is in example <exampleRef
letter="xCategoryChooser"
num="xCategoryChooser"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xCategoryChooser"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='1250'"
src="Resources/CategoryChooser.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>If you choose “Delete,” the category item will be deleted.</p
><p
>When you click on a category item in a word in the target phrase, the context menu shown in <exampleRef
letter="xWordContrextMenu"
num="xWordContrextMenu"
></exampleRef
> appears. This is the same as if you had clicked on the word item.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sEditFeature"
><secTitle
>Editing a feature</secTitle
><p
>When you click on a feature item in the tree, the context menu shown in <exampleRef
letter="xFeatureContextMenu"
num="xFeatureContextMenu"
></exampleRef
> appears.</p
><example
num="xFeatureContextMenu"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='1250'"
src="Resources/FeatureContextMenu.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>The Feature chooser appears if you choose “Edit.” Which features are listed in the chooser depends on whether the feature is in the source or the target portion of the tree diagram. <object
type="tFLExTrans"
></object
> gives <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> the list of features for the source <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> project and the target <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> project. In one case, the feature value chooser looked like what is in example <exampleRef
letter="xFeatureChooser"
num="xFeatureChooser"
></exampleRef
>.</p
><example
num="xFeatureChooser"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='1250'"
src="Resources/FeatureChooser.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>The number of Greek letter variable values shown defaults to four. You can set the number via the optional third command line parameter. See section <sectionRef
sec="sInvocation"
></sectionRef
>.</p
><p
>If you choose “Delete,” the feature item will be deleted.</p
><p
>The “Edit unmarked” option allows you to choose an overt value (not a Greek variable) for this feature. Doing this indicates what the unmarked or default value is for this feature. “Delete unmarked” is enabled only when there is already an unmarked feature value. You can use this to remove or delete this unmarked value.</p
><p
>Further, if the word is in the target phrase and the total number of features specified in the word and any of its affixes is greater than one, then you can use the “Edit ranking” option to specify the relative ranking of the feature for when the value for a feature may be missing in a given instance. When you click on “Edit ranking,” it brings up a chooser dialog showing which ranking values are available. When there are multiple features in an affix or a word, once you set the ranking of one feature, <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> will seek to assign a ranking to all features. It also will try to ensure no two features have the same ranking. You can use “Delete ranking” to remove a ranking from a feature. In fact, when you remove a ranking from one feature in an affix or a word, all other features in that affix or word will lose their ranking.</p
></section2
><section2
id="sEditAffix"
><secTitle
>Editing an affix</secTitle
><p
>When you click on an affix item in the tree, the context menu shown in <exampleRef
letter="xAffixContrextMenu"
num="xAffixContrextMenu"
></exampleRef
> appears.</p
><example
num="xAffixContrextMenu"
><chart
><img
XeLaTeXSpecial="scaled='1250'"
src="Resources/AffixContextMenu.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>Select the item you wish to use. They are as follows:</p
><ul
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Duplicate</object
>: creates a complete copy of the current affix.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Toggle affix type</object
>: changes the type from prefix to suffix or from suffix to prefix.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert feature</object
>: inserts a feature item. This is only available when a category has been set for the word this affix is a part of. The list of available features depends on the set of valid features defined in <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> for the category of the word.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert new prefix before</object
>: inserts a new affix item labeled as a prefix before the selected affix.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert new prefix after</object
>: inserts a new affix item labeled as a prefix after the selected affix.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert new suffix before</object
>: inserts a new affix item labeled as a suffix before the selected affix.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Insert new suffix after</object
>: inserts a new affix item labeled as a suffix after the selected affix.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Move left</object
>: moves the selected affix to the left.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Move right</object
>: moves the selected affix to the right.</li
><li
><object
type="tBold"
>Delete</object
>: removes the selected affix.</li
></ul
><p
></p
></section2
><section2
id="sCreatePermutations"
><secTitle
>Create permutations check box</secTitle
><p
>To the right of the rule name is a check box labeled "Create permutations." This check box is enabled only when the target portion has at least three words and one of them is marked as the head. If you want <object
type="tFLExTrans"
></object
> to create separate rules for each possible combination of the three or more word items, check this box.</p
></section2
></section1
><section1
id="sDisjointFeatureSets"
><secTitle
>Disjoint gender features</secTitle
><p
>In rare cases, you may need to use what we are calling “disjoint features.” Some <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> users implementing Bantu languages split the set of gender features into at least two sets. One set corresponds to the gender noun classes which also are marked as singular in number and the other set corresponds to the gender noun classes which are also marked as plural in number. When writing a rule via the <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
>, the idea is to use a name that will cover both of these sets. Example <exampleRef
letter="xFeatureSetEditor"
num="xFeatureSetEditor"
></exampleRef
> shows what you might do for a case like this.</p
><example
num="xFeatureSetEditor"
><chart
><img
src="Resources/DisjointGenderFaturesEditor.png"
></img
></chart
></example
><p
>The name that will be used in features in rules is in the “Name” field.</p
><p
>You can set this for either the source or the target language via the “Language” radio buttons.</p
><p
>The “Co-feature name” combo box lists all the features available in this language. You select the one that is common to each set of disjoint features. In this Bantu case, this is the “number” feature.</p
><p
>Below this is a slider control which lets you define between two and six pairs of a <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> feature and a value for this “co-feature.” Each pair has two combo boxes, one for the <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> feature and one for the value of the co-feature.. As you can see in example <exampleRef
letter="xFeatureSetEditor"
num="xFeatureSetEditor"
></exampleRef
>, in this <object
type="tFLEx"
></object
> project, the noun class gender feature has been split into two features: “Bantu1 singular” and “Bantu2 plural.”<endnote
id="nBantu1AndBantu2"
><p
>The “1” and the “2” are used merely for sorting purposes. This enables the singular to appear before the plural.</p
></endnote
> Notice that the singular disjoint feature uses the “sg” value of the “number” feature while the plural disjoint feature uses the ”pl” value of the “number” feature. This information enables the <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> to create appropriate transfer rules using the “BantuNounClass” cover term.</p
><p
>Whenever you have one of these disjoint feature sets defined and are choosing a feature to use in a word or affix, the name of the disjoint feature set will be listed in the possible feature values. You can then choose it as part of the rule like you would any other normal (non-disjoint) feature. In this example, you would see features like “BantuNounClass:α” and “BantuNounClass:β” in the list.</p
></section1
><section1
id="sRemembering"
><secTitle
>Restarting <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
></secTitle
><p
>Whenever you exit and restart <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
>, it will do the following:</p
><ol
><li
>remember its window size, location, and layout;</li
><li
>remember which rule you last chose;</li
><li
>remember the category chooser size, location, and layout;</li
><li
>remember feature chooser size, location, and layout;.</li
></ol
></section1
><section1
id="sKnownProblems"
><secTitle
>Known problems</secTitle
><p
>The following items are known to be less than desirable with this version of <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
>:</p
><ol
><li
><object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> only works on Windows.</li
><li
>The user interface is in English only (but can potentially be translated into other languages).</li
></ol
></section1
><section1
id="sSupport"
><secTitle
>Support</secTitle
><p
>If you have any questions with <object
type="tRuleGen"
></object
> or find bugs in it, please send an email to <link
href="mailto:blackhandrew@gmail.com"
>blackhandrew@gmail.com</link
>.</p
></section1
><backMatter
><endnotes
></endnotes
><references
></references
></backMatter
><languages
><language
id="lVernacular"
name="vernacular"
></language
><language
id="lGloss"
name="gloss"
></language
><language
id="en"
></language
><language
font-family="Ezra SIL"
id="lHebrew"
></language
><language
color="black"
font-family="Courier New"
id="lTreeExample"
></language
></languages
><types
><comment
>The following types are provided as pre-set examples. You may well want to create your own types that refer to one or more of these. You do that by typing in the names of the types in the types attribute of your type.</comment
><type
font-weight="bold"
id="tBold"
></type
><type
font-style="italic"
font-weight="bold"
id="tBoldItalic"
></type
><type
font-weight="bold"
id="tEmphasis"
></type
><type
id="tGrammaticalGloss"
types="tSmallCaps"
></type
><type
font-style="italic"
id="tItalic"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoOverline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-overline&quot;"
></type
><type
font-variant="normal"
id="tNoSmallCaps"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoStrikethrough"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-line-through&quot;"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:none"
id="tNoUnderline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;no-underline&quot;"
></type
><type
cssSpecial="text-decoration:overline"
id="tOverline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;overline&quot;"
></type
><type
font-style="normal"
font-variant="normal"
font-weight="normal"
id="tRegular"
></type
><type
font-family="Charis SIL Small Caps"
id="tSmallCaps"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="line-through"
cssSpecial="text-decoration:line-through"
id="tStrikethrough"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;line-through&quot;"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="subscript"
cssSpecial="vertical-align:sub;"
font-size="65%"
id="tSubscript"
xsl-foSpecial="baseline-shift='sub'"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="superscript"
cssSpecial="vertical-align:super;"
font-size="65%"
id="tSuperscript"
xsl-foSpecial="baseline-shift='super'"
></type
><type
XeLaTeXSpecial="underline"
cssSpecial="text-decoration:underline"
id="tUnderline"
xsl-foSpecial="text-decoration=&quot;underline&quot;"
></type
><comment
>Add your custom types here.</comment
><type
before="“Apply Checked Operations”"
id="tApplyOps"
></type
><type
before="Citation Form"
id="tCitationForm"
></type
><type
before="Citation Forms"
id="tCitationForms"
></type
><type
id="tDialogTitle"
></type
><type
before="Edit Operations"
id="tEditTab"
></type
><type
before="Edit Replace Operations"
id="tEditReplaceTab"
></type
><type
color="#800080"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
font-style="italic"
id="tEmpty"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-style="italic"
id="tErrorMessageItem"
></type
><type
color="red"
id="tErrorType"
></type
><type
color="blue"
font-family="Arial"
id="tGloss"
></type
><type
color="#009900"
font-family="Charis SIL"
font-weight="bold"
id="tKey"
></type
><type
color="red"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
id="tLexical"
></type
><type
color="maroon"
id="tMenuItem"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-family="Arial"
font-size="12pt"
id="tNonterminal"
></type
><type
before="9.1.18 Beta"
id="tFLExVersion"
></type
><type
before="700072"
id="tFWDatabaseVersion"
></type
><type
before="FieldWorks Language Explorer"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tFieldWorks"
></type
><type
before="FLEx"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tFLEx"
></type
><type
before="FLExTrans"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tFLExTrans"
></type
><type
before="FLExTrans Rule Assistant"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tRuleGen"
></type
><type
before="Run Operations"
id="tRunTab"
></type
><type
before="Stem Allomorph"
id="tStemAllo"
></type
><type
before="Stem Allomorphs"
id="tStemAllos"
></type
><type
before="Stem Name"
id="tStemName"
></type
><type
color="black"
font-family="Monospaced"
font-weight="bold"
id="tSynTagmeme"
></type
><type
color="navy"
id="tTool"
></type
><type
before="Variant Generator"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tVarGen"
></type
><type
color="purple"
id="tView"
></type
><type
before="XMLmind XML Editor"
color="navy"
font-style="italic"
id="tXXE"
></type
></types
></lingPaper
><publisherStyleSheet
><publisherStyleSheetName
>SIL International Paper Stylesheet</publisherStyleSheetName
><publisherStyleSheetVersion
>0.4.5</publisherStyleSheetVersion
><pageLayout
><pageWidth
>8.5in</pageWidth
><pageHeight
>11in</pageHeight
><pageTopMargin
>.7in</pageTopMargin
><pageBottomMargin
>.675in</pageBottomMargin
><pageInsideMargin
>1.5in</pageInsideMargin
><pageOutsideMargin
>1in</pageOutsideMargin
><useThesisSubmissionStyle
></useThesisSubmissionStyle
><headerMargin
>.25in</headerMargin
><footerMargin
>.25in</footerMargin
><paragraphIndent
>1em</paragraphIndent
><blockQuoteIndent
>.125in</blockQuoteIndent
><lineSpacing
></lineSpacing
><defaultFontFamily
>Charis SIL</defaultFontFamily
><basicPointSize
>12</basicPointSize
><footnotePointSize
>10</footnotePointSize
><footnoteLine
leaderlength="2in"
leaderpattern="rule"
textalign="left"
></footnoteLine
><linkLayout
color="blue"
decoration="underline"
><abbrRefLinkLayout
></abbrRefLinkLayout
><appendixRefLinkLayout
></appendixRefLinkLayout
><citationLinkLayout
></citationLinkLayout
><contentsLinkLayout
></contentsLinkLayout
><endnoteRefLinkLayout
></endnoteRefLinkLayout
><exampleRefLinkLayout
></exampleRefLinkLayout
><genericRefLinkLayout
></genericRefLinkLayout
><indexLinkLayout
></indexLinkLayout
><interlinearRefLinkLayout
></interlinearRefLinkLayout
><linkLinkLayout
></linkLinkLayout
><sectionRefLinkLayout
></sectionRefLinkLayout
><urlLinkLayout
></urlLinkLayout
></linkLayout
><headerFooterPageStyles
font-family="Times New Roman"
font-size="9pt"
font-style="italic"
><headerFooterFirstPage
><header
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></header
><footer
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><pageNumber
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></pageNumber
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></footer
></headerFooterFirstPage
><headerFooterOddEvenPages
><headerFooterEvenPage
><header
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><pageNumber
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></pageNumber
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><paperTitle
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></paperTitle
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></header
><footer
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></footer
></headerFooterEvenPage
><headerFooterOddPage
><header
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><sectionTitle
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></sectionTitle
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><pageNumber
font-size="smaller"
font-style="italic"
></pageNumber
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></header
><footer
><leftHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></leftHeaderFooterItem
><centerHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></centerHeaderFooterItem
><rightHeaderFooterItem
><nothing
></nothing
></rightHeaderFooterItem
></footer
></headerFooterOddPage
></headerFooterOddEvenPages
></headerFooterPageStyles
></pageLayout
><frontMatterLayout
><comment
>Front Matter Layout</comment
><titleLayout
font-size="18pt"
font-weight="bold"
pagebreakbefore="yes"
spacebefore="1.25in"
startonoddpage="yes"
textalign="center"
></titleLayout
><subtitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
textalign="center"
></subtitleLayout
><authorLayout
font-style="italic"
textalign="center"
></authorLayout
><affiliationLayout
font-style="italic"
textalign="center"
></affiliationLayout
><emailAddressLayout
font-size="90%"
textalign="center"
></emailAddressLayout
><presentedAtLayout
font-size="10pt"
textalign="center"
textbefore="Presented at "
></presentedAtLayout
><dateLayout
font-size="10pt"
textalign="center"
></dateLayout
><versionLayout
font-size="10pt"
textalign="center"
></versionLayout
><contentsLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
useperiodafterappendixletter="yes"
></contentsLayout
><abstractLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></abstractLayout
><acknowledgementsLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></acknowledgementsLayout
><prefaceLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></prefaceLayout
></frontMatterLayout
><bodyLayout
><comment
>Body Layout</comment
><section1Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section1Layout
><section2Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-size="12pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="12pt"
textalign="start"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section2Layout
><section3Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-style="italic"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="12pt"
textalign="start"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section3Layout
><section4Layout
><sectionTitleLayout
font-style="italic"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="12pt"
textalign="start"
></sectionTitleLayout
></section4Layout
><section5Layout
ignore="yes"
><sectionTitleLayout
></sectionTitleLayout
></section5Layout
><section6Layout
ignore="yes"
><sectionTitleLayout
></sectionTitleLayout
></section6Layout
></bodyLayout
><backMatterLayout
><comment
>Back Matter Layout</comment
><acknowledgementsLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></acknowledgementsLayout
><appendixLayout
><appendixTitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textafterletter=". "
textalign="center"
></appendixTitleLayout
></appendixLayout
><glossaryLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></glossaryLayout
><referencesTitleLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></referencesTitleLayout
><xi:include
href="SILInternationalReferencesStylesheet.xml"
xpointer="element(/1)"
xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
></xi:include
><indexLayout
font-size="14pt"
font-weight="bold"
spaceafter="12pt"
spacebefore="24pt"
textalign="center"
></indexLayout
></backMatterLayout
><contentLayout
><comment
>Document Content Layout</comment
><exampleLayout
indent-after=".125in"
indent-before=".125in"
></exampleLayout
><interlinearSourceStyle
></interlinearSourceStyle
><endnoteRefLayout
></endnoteRefLayout
><figureLayout
captionLocation="after"
><figureLabelLayout
textafter=" "
></figureLabelLayout
><figureNumberLayout
></figureNumberLayout
><figureCaptionLayout
textbefore=" "
></figureCaptionLayout
></figureLayout
><figureRefLayout
></figureRefLayout
><tablenumberedLayout
captionLocation="after"
><tablenumberedLabelLayout
font-weight="bold"
textafter=" "
></tablenumberedLabelLayout
><tablenumberedNumberLayout
textafter=": "
></tablenumberedNumberLayout
><tablenumberedCaptionLayout
font-style="italic"
textbefore="  "
></tablenumberedCaptionLayout
></tablenumberedLayout
><tablenumberedRefLayout
></tablenumberedRefLayout
></contentLayout
></publisherStyleSheet
></styledPaper
></xlingpaper
>
